<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on The Kentros Lab</title>
    <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on The Kentros Lab</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/kentroslab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/kentroslab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-kentros-lab&#34;&gt;The Kentros lab&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to better understand the neural circuitry underlying learning and memory and to develop powerful tools to precisely investigate questions relevant to brain disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team is composed of molecular biologists developping viral and transgenic tools, and physiologists using these tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Research Questions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do the different neuron types in a neuronal circuit contribute to the complex process of learning and memory?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it possible to develop highly precise tools and therapies by targeting specific cell types in the brain?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/anelau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/anelau/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello this is Ane&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/annikau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/annikau/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hello this is Annika&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/bianca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/bianca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hello this is bianca&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/chrschr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/chrschr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hello this is christina&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/cliff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/cliff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After his doctoral work on Potassium channels with Bernardo Rudy at NYU, Cliff Kentros investigated the relationship between place cells and memory during his postdoctoral work with Robert Muller at SUNY Downstate and Eric Kandel at Columbia University.  His laboratory takes advantage of his dual molecular and neurophysiological background by combining the anatomical specificity of molecular genetics with in vivoelectrophysiological recordings and anatomical analysis, first at the University of Oregon and now at the Kavli Institute of Systems Neuroscience at NTNU in Trondheim, Norway, where he is Professor of Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one feature above all that differentiates the mammalian brain from from all other biological structures is its anatomical complexity: the human brain contains an estimated 100 billion neurons, each connected to an average of 10,000 other neurons and organized into innumerable distinct cell types. One cannot understand electronic circuits without a detailed circuit diagram and the ability to manipulate single circuit elements while recording from others. Similarly, it is impossible to fully understand brain function without being able to identify and manipulate specific neuronal cell types while recording from other circuit elements. For this reason, my laboratory both performs ​in vivo​ recordings from awake, behaving animals, and attempts to generate novel molecular genetic tools capable of driving transgene in specific neuronal cell types, particularly in those parts of the brain involved in learning and memory. Recent years have seen remarkable advances in molecular genetic tools for the elucidation and manipulation of neural circuits, but the means to deliver such transgenes with the requisite specificity has lagged far behind. One can only address the manifest complexity of the brain by co-oping the genetic machinery which underlies it, but while most genes are expressed in the brain, they are unfortunately almost always expressed in multiple cell types. My laboratory has recently taken a novel tactic to address this problem by using transcriptional ​cis​-regulatory sequences specific to particular microdissected brain regions to drive transgene expression in particular cell types of that region, an approach we call Enhancer-Driven Gene Expression (EDGE). Our recent work has shown that EDGE yields anatomical specificity of transgene expression far surpassing that of the parent gene&amp;hellip; i.e. one can obtain high degrees of anatomical specificity from ​nonspecific​ genes. Moreover, these enhancers are typically small enough to fit inside viral vectors, obviating the need for transgenic animals and opening up such anatomically-specific approaches to any species. This last feature not only will bring circuit-specific manipulations to any model species, it has the promise to open up entirely new circuit-specific therapeutic avenues to pathologies of the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/eliserol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/eliserol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hello this is elise&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/joachsig/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/joachsig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hello this is joachim&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/luciede/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/luciede/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lucie joined the Kentros lab in September 2018, through the EU funded scheme &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mgate.eu/&#34;&gt;M-GATE ITN&lt;/a&gt;. Her main work focuses on investigating how the anterior cingulate cortex is involved in memory formation and consolidation, using miniaturized head-mounted fluorescence icroscopes to perform neuronal calcium-imaging in freely moving mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously from joining the lab, Lucie gained her master degree in Neuroscience from University College London, where she worked under the supervision of Dr Nick Robinson in the lab of Michael Hausser on a project investigating the causal role of CA1 place cells in navigation and spatial memory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/marcussf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/marcussf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hello this is marcus&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/marialet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/marialet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hello this is maria letizia&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/matteo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/matteo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hello this is matteo&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/miguelc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/miguelc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hello this is miguel&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/omtchadne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/omtchadne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oscarjoined the Kentros lab in June 2018, through the EU funded scheme &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mgate.eu/&#34;&gt;M-GATE ITN&lt;/a&gt;. His main work focuses on investigating &amp;hellip;..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously from joining the lab, Oscar gained his master degree in Neuroscience from University College London, where he worked under the supervision of Dr Shinichiro Tsutsumi in the lab of Michael Hausser on a project investigating &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/qiangwei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/qiangwei/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hello this is Qiangwei&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/stefanb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/stefanb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hello this is stefan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/valentdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscarchadney.github.io/authors/valentdi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hello this is vale&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
